Who defeated the global jihad? The American military did, the American soldiers did, with their allies, fighting in faraway battlefields. And perhaps, a time will come when they get the rightful credit for it. So all these factors, and many more besides, we don't even fully understand some of them yet, these came together to defeat a monstrosity as big as bin Ladenism, the global jihad, you needed this group effort. Now, not all of these things will work in local jihad. The American military is not going to march into Nigeria to take on Boko Haram, and it's unlikely that SEAL Team Six will rappel into the homes of al Shabaab's leaders and take them out. But many of these other factors that were in play are now even stronger than before. Half the work is already done. We don't have to reinvent the wheel. The notion of violent jihad in which more Muslims are killed than any other kind of people is already thoroughly discredited. We don't have to go back to that. Satellite television and the Internet are informing and empowering young Muslims in exciting new ways. And the Arab Spring has produced governments, many of them Islamist governments, who know that, for their own self-preservation, they need to take on the extremists in their midsts. We don't need to persuade them, but we do need to help them, because they haven't really come to this place before. The good news, again, is that a lot of the things they need we already have, and we are very good at giving: economic assistance, not just money, but expertise, technology, knowhow, private investment, fair terms of trade, medicine, education, technical support for training for their police forces to become more effective, for their anti-terror forces to become more efficient. We've got plenty of these things. Some of the other things that they need we're not very good at giving. Maybe nobody is. Time, patience, subtlety, understanding -- these are harder to give. I live in New York now. Just this week, posters have gone up in subway stations in New York that describe jihad as savage. But in all the many years that I have covered the Middle East, I have never been as optimistic as I am today that the gap between the Muslim world and the West is narrowing fast, and one of the many reasons for my optimism is that, because I know there are millions, hundreds of millions of people, Muslims like that old imam in Tunis, who are reclaiming this word and restoring to its original, beautiful purpose. Bin Laden is dead. Bin Ladenism has been defeated. His definition of jihad can now be expunged. To that jihad we can say, "Goodbye. Good riddance." To the real jihad we can say, "Welcome back. Good luck." Thank you. (Applause)
¿Quién derrotó a la yihad global? Lo hizo el ejército estadounidense, los soldados estadounidenses y sus aliados, luchando en campos de batalla lejanos. Y quizá llegue el día en que se les brinde el crédito merecido. Todos estos factores, y muchos otros, algunos de los cuales todavía no entendemos, se unieron para derrotar a una monstruosidad tan grande como el binladenismo, la yihad global; se necesitaba de este esfuerzo grupal. Aunque no todos estos funcionarán contra la yihad local. El ejército estadounidense no marchará hacia Nigeria para hacerse cargo de Boko Haram, y es improbable que el 6° equipo SEAL irrumpa en los hogares de los líderes de Al Shabaab y los derrote. Pero muchos de los otros factores que contribuyeron se han fortalecido. La mitad del trabajo está hecho. No es necesario reinventar la rueda. La idea de una yihad violenta en que la mayoría de las víctimas son musulmanes está completamente desacreditada. No tenemos que regresar a eso. La televisión satelital y el internet están informando y confiriendo poder a jóvenes musulmanes, en formas novedosas e interesantes. Y la primavera árabe ha producido gobiernos, muchos de ellos islamistas, que saben que por su propia seguridad, deben encargarse de los extremistas en sus poblaciones. No es necesario persuadirles, pero sí ayudarles porque no han enfrentado esta situación anteriormente. La buena noticia es que mucho de lo que necesitan ya lo tenemos, y somos muy buenos dándolo: asistencia económica, no solo dinero, sino asesoría, tecnología, experiencia, inversión privada, términos justos de comercio, medicina, educación, asistencia técnica para entrenamiento para que sus fuerzas policiacas sean más efectivas, para que sus fuerzas antiterroristas sean más eficientes. Tenemos suficiente de esto. Y algunas otras cosas que necesitan, no somos muy buenos dándolas. Quizá nadie lo es. Tiempo, paciencia, sutileza, comprensión, son más difíciles de dar. Ahora vivo en Nueva York. Justo esta semana se han colocado carteles en las estaciones del metro que describen a la yihad como salvaje. Pero en todos los años que he cubierto el Oriente Medio, nunca me he sentido tan optimista como hoy en que la brecha entre el mundo islámico y Occidente se reduzca rápidamente, y una de las razones para mi optimismo es que sé que hay millones, cientos de millones de personas, musulmanes como el viejo imán en Túnez, que están reclamando esta palabra y devolviéndola a su hermoso significado original. Bin Laden está muerto. El binladenismo ha sido derrotado. Ahora se puede desechar su definición de yihad. A esa yihad podemos decirle, “Adiós. Hasta nunca”. A la yihad auténtica podemos decirle, “Bienvenida de nuevo. Mucha suerte”. Gracias. (Aplausos)